准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
马戏团大破坏
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
你们好  我可爱的金主
Hello, me lovely paying--
客人们
customers?
大家都去哪了
Where is everybody?
午餐时间
Lunchtime
工作日
"Work day"
旧月
工作日
钱
Money
还在跳动
Still have a pulse
汽笛风琴音乐
Calliope music?
我进恐怖片里了
I'm in a horror movie
等一下
Wait a minute
什么
What?
不会吧
Oh, no
马戏团
The circus?
怪不得没客人来
No wonder there aren't any customers
又见面了  老螃蟹
Hello again, Krabs
驯兽师泥蟹
Ringmaster Mudcrab?
这太不像话了
This is outrageous
不准在我店门口停你家的小破马戏团
You can't park your flea circus on my property
我表亲身为市长
Since my cousin is the mayor
给了我城建许可证批准我停
this city permit says I can
既然你生意不好
Since you won't be busy
送你一张马戏团的门票
here's a free ticket to the circus
让你看看你的钱都跑哪去了
so you can see where all your money went
务必要来尝尝我们这里的棉花糖
Don't forget to try our cotton candy
你客人们都把这玩意当蟹黄堡吃
Your customers are gobbling it up like it was Krabby Patties
天啊  是马戏团
Oh, boy, it's the circus
没错  每年那个驯兽师泥蟹
Yes, every year that Ringmaster Mudcrab
都会来裤头村  偷走我的客人
rolls into town and steals me customers
可今年他居然把他的破马戏团
But this year he's parked his shabby tent show
直接停我家店门前
right on me property
去买个蟹黄堡吧
Let's get a Krabby Patty
不要  改去那家马戏团吧
No, let's go to the circus instead
既然没活干  我先开溜
Well, since there's no work, I'll be going
去马戏团
To the circus
To the circus?
去马戏团
To the circus
破坏掉它
To destroy it
To destroy it?
破坏掉它
To destroy it
To destroy it?
不对  小子
No, no, boy-o
不是破坏
not destroy
我是说  过去嗨
I said "enjoy"
我们要去马戏团边看边嗨
We're going to enjoy the circus
我们要去马戏团
We're going to the circus
而且老少皆宜
And it'll be fun for all ages
票卖光了  全场又是座无虚席
We've got another sold-out show today, troupe
大家务必演得精彩  让观众绝对难忘
So let's give them a spectacle they'll never forget
对  观众绝对忘不掉
Yeah, they'll never forget it, all right
老螃蟹  是你吗
Krabs, is that you?
没错
That's right
就是老螃蟹
It's Krabs
我不争气的废物员工们
And me own crew of incompetent misfits
会把你马戏团变成笑柄
will make such a mockery of your circus
让你一辈子没脸再回来裤头村
that you'll be drummed out of Bikini Bottom forever
开门
Open up
快给我开门
Open up, I say
蟹老板  我不是很明白
Hey, Mr. Krabs, I don't get it
我们为什么要穿成这样
Why are we dressed like this?
因为今天马戏团里的人全病了
Because everyone in the circus is sick today
我朋友驯兽师
and my friend the ringmaster
叫我们顶一下表演
asked us to take over the show
所以我就是
So I'll be
新任驯兽师
the new ringmaster
章鱼哥在哪
Where's Squidward?
我非得这样吗
Do I have to do this?
你样子挺好的
You look great
你的悲情模样已经让我泪目了
The pathos is already moving me to tears
表演要开始了
Show's starting
大家请就位
Places, everyone
各位白痴们笨蛋们
Dummies and numbskulls
老捣蛋鬼小捣蛋鬼们
spoiled brats of all ages
欢迎观赏全世界最烂的表演
welcome to the crummiest show on Earth
白痴
Dummies?
笨蛋
Numbskulls?
太没礼貌了
How rude
他肯定是那种嘴臭驯兽师
He must be one of those insult ringmasters
那样的话  好有搞笑效果
Well, in that case, he's funny
奇怪
That's weird
观众还挺喜欢
They actually enjoyed that
等着让他们看看第一出表演
Well, wait till they see this first act
一定会让他们全讨厌
They're gonna hate it
请大家看向我头顶上的钢丝
I call your attention to the high wire above me
有请小丑海绵大废物
Introducing Sponge-O the Incompetent
是海绵宝宝
That's SpongeBob
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
小朋友们好
Hey, kids
没错  是不是很不像话啊
Yes, folks, isn't he appalling?
马上退钱离场吧
Leave now for a full refund
快给我掉网里
Fall into the net already
放海胆逼他掉
Urchins should do it
不要
Oh, no
不不不
No, no, no
我下台了
I'm out
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you
快放我出去
Let me out of here
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我会把我们都救出去的
I'll get us out of here
迟早会的
Eventually
好了  大家都安静
All right, shut up, everybody
闭嘴
Shut it
请由我来指明出口
Allow me to point out the exits
因为下一出表演
because this next act
绝对会让大家大失所望
is sure to disappoint you
请大家不准掌声欢迎小丑章鱼
Don't put your hands together for Squid-O
全世界最伤心的小丑
the world's saddest clown
什么
What?
观众不应该同情他的啊
They're not supposed to sympathize with him
别对人家啊了
Don't aw him
对他喝倒彩
Boo him
什么
What the
台下观众智商太低  看啥都觉得好看
This idiot crowd is too easily entertained
最后一出表演
I've got one last act
绝对能让他们恨上这座马戏团
that'll make them hate this circus
就快好了
Almost there
全体海熊  出去
All right, you sea bears, out
去去去去去
Out, out, out, out, out
派大星
Patrick
怎么了
What's up?
进去
Get in
接下来这场烂得可怜又二流的表演
For our next pitiful, second-rate form of entertainment
主角是训练无素的跳舞海熊
we have the mournful sight of a trained dancing sea bear
而且还是个假熊
that's a total fraud
是派大星
That's Patrick
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
你好  裤头村
Hello, Bikini Bottom
快到球上去  假熊
Get on the ball, fake bear
跳舞
and dance
他对假熊好凶
He's being mean to the fake bear
终于有用了
It's finally working
确实
Yes, I agree
这表演最烂了
This show is the worst
我要是你的话
If I were you
早就愤怒离场要求退钱
I'd storm out and demand my money back
然后拿着这钱去蟹堡王花
and then go spend it at the Krusty Krab
到你了
Your turn
快到球上去  驯兽师
On the ball, Ringmaster
跳舞
and dance
快到球上去
On the ball
好好
Yeah, yeah
好
Yeah
快到球上去
On the ball
行行
Okay, okay
我这就上去
I'll get on
好了  看到没
There, see?
天啊  被迫上球跑
Oh, boy, I'm dragging
我要亲自去斗斗老螃蟹
I'll take care of Krabs myself
老螃蟹
Krabs
你哪来的胆子  敢把我的马戏团变成
How dare you turn my circus into a--
就是  马戏团
well, a circus?
你又哪来的胆子把我的蟹堡王变成
Well, how dare you turn me restaurant into a
没人来的蟹堡王
empty restaurant?
你荡得走  但你躲不掉
You can swing, but you can't hide
看来你命悬一线啊
Looks like you're hung out to dry
海胆
Urchins
快下去
Get 'em off me
什么
What?
没有我  你们什么都不是
You'd be nothing without me
老螃蟹
Krabs?
我要把你的壳炸个洞出来
I'm gonna blast a hole right through your carapace
老不死的戏子
you corny carny
我要把你牙齿全给崩了
I'm gonna pound out all of your teeth
苍蝇馆子破老板
you ridiculous restauranteur
一周后
章鱼哥  你觉得蟹老板
Hey, Squidward, do you think Mr. Krabs
还会回蟹堡王来吗
will ever come back to the Krusty Krab?
大概率不会
I doubt it
他现在赚的钱比以前还要多不少呢
He's making more money now than he ever did
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
请大家观赏你们眼前最壮观的景象
behold the most incredible sight you'll ever see
神奇无比  活力满满
It's amazing, and it's alive
大家快来看
Step right up, folks
早知道能赚这么多钱
If I knew I'd make this much money
老早以前就该拿自己当炮打你了
I'd have cannonballed into you a long time ago
我爱马戏团
I love the circus
全世界就数这个最赚钱
It's the greatest dough on Earth
珊迪帮帮忙
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
早安  阳光
Good morning, sunshine
早安  珊迪
Morning, Sandy
好家伙
Little doggie
经历了这么多月以来的精密计算
After months of careful calculations
我的不合逻辑生物实验就快完成了
my bio-illogical experiment is almost done
珊迪  帮帮忙
Sandy, help me
我的天啊  海绵宝宝
Hopping holes, SpongeBob
怎么了
What's wrong?
你一定要快过来一下
You got to come quick
我的闹钟坏掉了
My alarm clock is broken
你的闹钟吗
Your alarm clock, huh?
确定得要现在就去修闹钟吗
Are you sure we need to take care of that just now?
确定
Yes
好吧
All right
我连插头都拔了  就是关不掉
I even pulled out the plug, and I can't shut it off
得动动脑子解决了
I got to get my brain working on this
我知道问题在哪了
I see the problem
谢了  大脑
Thanks, brain
你的海绵手指实在太过软萌了
Your spongy finger is just too darn soft and cute
按不动按钮
to press the switch
放心好了  亲爱的
Don't worry, darling
我会解决的
I'll fix it
谢谢珊迪
Thanks, Sandy
我等不及要回去做实验了
I'm just itching to get back to my experiment
喂
Hello?
珊迪  帮帮忙
Sandy, help me
飞天魔鬼
Flying Dutchman?
珊迪
Sandy
那只是幅画
That's just a painting
我在这下面
I'm down here
你怎么了  飞天魔鬼
What happened to you, Dutchy?
都这样了还看不出来
What's it look like?
有个巫婆把我关进水晶球里了
A witch trapped me inside a crystal ball
快放我出去
Now get me out of here
珊迪  我就全靠你了
Sandy, I am in your hands
我来试一下
Let me try a little
也许再这么来一下
Or maybe some of this
没什么用
Well, that didn't work
快动脑啊
Come on, brain
有了
That's it
我要用农场科技来解决
I need to use good old farm science on this one
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你把我孵出来了
You hatched me good
等一下
Wait a minute
我还是很小
I'm still tiny
怎么会这样  珊迪
What gives, Sandy?
很抱歉打扰了  科研人员奇克斯
I'm sorry to interrupt, Science Officer Cheeks
海底空间局
but the Undersea Space Agency
需要你立刻前来协助
needs your immediate assistance
遵命
Absolutely
抱歉  飞天魔鬼
Sorry, Dutchy
使命在召唤我
Duty calls
一颗巨大陨石正直冲地球飞来
A giant meteor is headed straight for Earth
跟往常一样  珊迪
and as usual, Sandy
只有你才能拯救我们
you're the only one that can save us
包在我身上  长官
You can count on me, sir
不好意思  地球
Pardon me, Earth
你得让开一点点
you'll need to scooch over a bit
坏陨石又绕回来了
That sidewinding stone is a-coming back
陨石不乖
Bad meteor, bad
谢谢珊迪
Thanks, Sandy
真是太棒了
Sweet mother-of-pearl
我终于可以一个人安安静静做
I can finally be all alone with my--
我的实验成功了
My experiment worked
好大
It's huge
先在这等着
Wait right there
骑兵马上就来
Cavalry's coming
我是山核桃珊迪
I am Pecan Sandy
你好  山核桃珊迪
Howdy, Pecan Sandy
我是珊迪一号
I'm Sandy Number One
我在实验室把你创造出来
and I created you in my lab
让你帮我做家务
to help me with all the chores
期间我整天都要出门在外解救大家
while I'm out saving people all day
你先从出去倒垃圾开始帮起吧
You can start by taking out the garbage
山核桃珊迪讨厌出去倒垃圾
Pecan Sandy hates taking out the garbage
对不起  山核桃珊迪
I'm sorry, Pecan Sandy
你不用出去倒垃圾了
You don't have to take out the garbage
那你愿不愿意洗盘子
How about washing the dishes?
山核桃珊迪不是你的女仆
Pecan Sandy is not your maid
实验与预期完全相反
This experiment is backfiring on me
要想办法  想办法
I got to think, got to think
我的大脑累昏头了  想不动
My bushwhacked brain is too fried to think
好  该来使出蛮力了
All right, time to use some brawn
好吧
Okay
看来只能把事情放一放
Looks like I'm gonna need to pull the rip cord
呼叫紧急联系人
and call my emergency contact
喂
Hello?
娜琳  帮帮忙
Narlene, help me
娜琳  你在吗
Narlene, are you there?
简而言之  那个就是珊迪
Well, that's Sandy in a nutshell
坚 果 壳 里
我也很想笑  娜琳
I'd like to laugh about it, too, Narlene
能不能快帮我出来
Can you get me out of here soon?
一定会快得不得了
Sooner than you think
真心谢谢你  乡下姐妹
Thank you kindly, country buddy
我先盲猜一下
Don't tell me
你在实验室创造了个山核桃珊迪
You created a Pecan Sandy in your lab
它突然发狂  你要我帮忙阻止它
It's gone on a rampage, and you need my help to stop it
对  差不多就那样
Yep, that about covers it
我来想想看
Let me give it a think
有了
I got it
要打败山核桃珊迪只有一个办法
There's only one way to pummel pesky pecan into pie--
就是上脚
with your feet
但凡做什么事你都上脚  娜琳
That's your answer for everything, Narlene
我喜欢
And I like it
三脚战术不错  娜琳
Nice triple footsie, Narlene
夸得真好
Now, ain't you sweet?
我也喜欢你的夹脚摔战术  珊迪
I liked your toe-jam slam, too, Sandy
我妈才没把我养成逃兵
My mama didn't raise no quitters
我要把这腌椰菜桶的底细查个明白
I'm getting to the bottom of this pickle barrel
要小心  娜琳
Watch it, Narlene
跟我说说  山核桃珊迪
Tell me, Pecan Sandy
你为什么会生气
why are you so angry?
山核桃珊迪会生气
Pecan Sandy angry
因为她创造我是想让我倒垃圾
because she created me to take out her garbage
你做了什么
You did what, now?
这样我也会发狂的
Heck, I'd go on a rampage, too
你是怎么了
What possessed you?
那都是个馊主意
It was a bad idea
我承认了
I admit it now
就理论上说
Look, on paper
既然事情经过我都了解了
Well, now that I know the whole story
我的山民智慧告诉我
my hill-folk wisdom tells me
只有一个办法
there's only one way
可以解决山核桃珊迪的问题
to crack this nutty problem
要放了她  让她自由生活
We got to let her loose to live her own life
山核桃珊迪想要的  我全都要
I want whatever Pecan Sandy wants
我是山核桃珊迪
I am Pecan Sandy
我想做什么就做什么
And me do what me wants
欢迎你随时回来
Y'all come back anytime
关
好了  我们可以休息了
All right, we've earned a break
我终于快乐了
Me finally happy
珊迪  帮帮忙
Sandy, help us